ALESSANDRO LOI

+1 (206) 206-9919 | thealessandroloi@gmail.com | Seattle, WA | linkedin.com/in/alessandroloi | holybuz.github.io/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Lead Software Engineer with 10+ years of experience in mobile app development, specializing in building mobile SDKs, IoT solutions and high-impact products. Scaled teams from 1 to 10+ engineers and led my previous company to a successful exit.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Seam

Founding Mobile Engineer

2024 - Present

- Leading the development of Seam's mobile team and our brand-new Mobile SDK in Swift and Kotlin.
- Integrated two major IoT device brands into Seam's SDK, onboarding thousands of new devices.

Keyless

Lead Software Engineer

2021 - 2023

- Designed and implemented core features of the Biometric Authenticator Apps and Keyless SDKs.
- Led a cross-functional mobile team to ship 10 features within 8 months.
- Recruited, trained, and mentored 5+ mobile engineers.
- Accelerated time-to-market for new features by 60% by enabling cross-functional collaboration.

Keyless

Senior Software Engineer, iOS

2020 - 2021

- Designed and built the Keyless iOS SDK, improving app performance by 80%.
- Delivered MVPs that generated over \$1M in revenue.
- Refactored legacy code from Objective-C to Swift, reducing SDK bugs by 70%.
- Integrated 2 proprietary C++ frameworks into the Keyless SDK.

Oddschecker

Software Engineer, iOS

2019 - 2020

- Developed a crucial component of the Betting App, contributing to 75% of company revenue.
- Refactored legacy code from Objective-C to Swift, resulting in a 99% crash-free app.

BautifulBox

Lead Software Engineer, iOS

2019 - 2019

- Designed, developed, and maintained the iOS App, delivering 2 MVPs for IoT solutions.
- Supervised the development of the CES demo, increasing product inquiries by 75%.

YaAR

Head of Engineering - Co-Founder

2016 - 2018

- Co-founded an Augmented Reality Startup, pioneering browser-based AR Framework.
- Directed a diverse 22-member team across 4 countries, building a strong team culture.

Heartbit Interactive

Software Engineer

2013 - 2013

• Worked on tech demos for 5 major gaming events that reached over 200,000 players.

Freelancer

Software Engineer

2012 - 2016

Developed and launched 15+ iOS Apps and MVPs, from gaming to social networks.

EDUCATION

City University of Seattle

Master's, Computer Science

University of Cagliari

Bachelor's, Computer Science

SKILLS

Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C, C/C++, JavaScript, Python, Java, Ruby, Kotlin, GraphQL

Frameworks: SwiftUI, UIKit, RxSwift, Cocoa, CoreData, Modern Concurrency, Combine, CoreBluetooth, GCD, ARKit, MapKit

Architectures: MVVM, MVC, TCA, VIPER

Tools: AWS, GCP, Git, Firebase, TestFlight, Fastlane, XCode, Gitlab, Github, Figma, CI/CD

Soft Skills: Cross-Platform, Unit Testing, Kanban, Design Patterns, Encryption, OAuth, Agile, Scrum, JSON